# Prakash Kalari

9704598006

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/prakashkalari/

https://www.hackerrank.com/prakashnani130?hr\_r=1

□ prakashkalari1809@gmail.com

https://github.com/prakash200

https://www.codechef.com/users/prakash\_200

#### **Profile**

Competitive programmer and Creative developer who is passionate about product building and exploring new Technology. Fast Learner with experience in building products for clients. Remain calm and stay focussed in pressure situations. Constantly motivated and dedicated towards Work and Goals. Never give up attitude with Multitasking workability. Target on daily basis. Strongly believe in Team Work and loves to lead a Team.

#### **Education**

2019 – 2023

Amritapuri, India

Amrita Vishwa vidyapeetam University
Electrical and Computer Engineering CGPA 8.6

2019

Intermediate

Hyderabad, India

Delta Junior College
Maths, Physics and Chemistery (MPC) CGPA 9.2

# **Professional Experience**

2021/03 - 2021/11

2021/03 – 2021/1 Remote

## Django & Image Processing Internship

Konnect2digital services

- Extracted various companies website data by performing web scraping using libraries called selenium and beautiful soup with the help of python scripts.
- Built Machine Learning Pipelines for the ML project from the scratch till Deployment of the Models and Data Annotation Tools.
- Built an computer vision Model for Text detection on certificates using YOU ONLY LOOK AT ONCE (YOLO) Algorithm.
- Worked with Open-source Data Annotation projects and Developed data preprocessing , Augumentation etc ... features with the help of Django, Html, CSS , Javascript.
- Dockerization of projects in Multiple Docker Containers.
- Worked with Relational databases like Postgres and sql.
- Deploying projects with Nginx and Gunicorn in Production Environment.
- Worked with AWS Ec2 linux instance for deploying Projects in AWS.
- Used Git for making commits from different branches of a repository in Gitlab.

2020/08 – 2021/01 Remote

# Data Science and Machine Learning Learner

Board infinity

- Explored Advanced Features of Microsoft Excel , Tableau and analyzed Datasets with the help of them.
- Worked with Advanced SQL Queries and analyzed the data of different databases.
- Analyzed datasets and performed Exploratory data analysis (EDA) using python.
- Built Classification and Regression Machine Learning models.
- Devloped deep Learning Agorithms like ANN and CNN on datasets like Mnist.

#### **Skills**

Problem Solving Data Analytics | Machine Learning | Deep Learning | Data Science Data Structures and Algorithms | Html | Python | C | Django | RDMS | Git | Web Scraping Advanced Excel | Tableau | Docker | AWS EC2

### **Projects**

2022/03 - present Crop Recommendation using Iot and Machine Learning • Using lot devices real time data will be collected from fields and passed to ML model which predicts suitable crops. Some of the Key performance indicators (KPI)'s which are used for testing are Nitrogen, Phosphorus, Potassium, PH, Humidity. 2022/05 - 2022/06**CLI-APP** for checking Weather Report · This is purely built on Python scripts, with no frameworks involved, and uses SQLite as a database. Open weather APIs are used for fetching the data. • In this Users can sign up, log in, update profiles and check a given city's weather report. 2021/08 - 2021/08**Data Scraping of Ecoideaz Ventures** • Using Selenium and bs4 libraries python scripts were written for Extracting the company's data. Organization data was scrapped based on their states and Exported into a JSON file. 2021/03 - 2021/04Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) on Play store Ratings Data Preprocessing and Null Value Handling was done using different preprocessing techniques. Analyzed the Features of dataset using Matplotlib, seaborn and Bulit charts, graphs like Barchart, Heat map, Box plots etc... and conclusions are made from each plots 2021/01 - 2021/02Automobile price Prediction using Machine Learning • Understanding how exactly the prices vary with the independent variables. Built a Multiple Regression Model for predicting Automobile price. Analyzation of covid-19 and super store data using Excel & Tableau 2020/11 - 2020/12 Covid-19 victims in India of February, March and April Months 2020 data was collected and made detailed analysis of covid-19 using EXCEL and found meaning insights from the data. Super store sales data was analyzed using Tableau sofware and built dynamic charts. Analyzing HR and NORTHWIND databases using SQL 2020/10 - 2020/10

 Using Sql (Structured Query Language), queries are written for data fetching and solving different use cases in the platform called Mysql workbench.

### Certificates

• Intern Completion Certificate from Konnect2digital • Data science course completion certificate from Board services 🗷 Infinity 12 • Problem Solving Certificate from hackerRank ☑ • Python Certificate from HackerRank 🛮 Languages • Telugu Hindi • English

# **Hobbies**

• Playing Cricket, Chess Travelling Reading

# Achievements

- 5-star rating and earned a Golden badge in HackeRank under Problem solving.
- Codechef Contests points of 1692 with a 3-star rating.